Illia Sotnyk

QUALITY ASSURANCE AUTOMATION ENGINEER / SDET 368-399-4694

illia.sotnyk@gmail.com

EDMONTON, AB

PROFILE

QA automation engineer with almost 10 years experience in manual and automated testing for a variety of products, including Desktop apps, Web apps and Mobile apps (both iOS and Android). Used to implement test frameworks from scratch (including API testing). Was able to maintain the quality of the project from zero to successful MVP while leading the QA subteam.

EXPERIENCE

QA Automation Engineer | Lohika | Odesa, Ukraine (Hybrid and Remote)

September 2017- February 2024

Lohika (later acquired by Capgemini Engineering) is a digital authority that advises and provides at the cutting-edge of technology. With US headquarters in San Mateo, CA and European headquarters in Lviv, Odesa, Kyiv (Ukraine) the company employed more than 1500 people in offices in 2021.

The first project was related to lifecycle management and system monitoring software. As
a big team of dedicated QA Automation engineers we were responsible for automated
testing of Web UI and also semi-automated testing of installation and deployment of
software. We were working in very close collaboration with our stakeholders in Germany.
Team: 16 QA Automation Engineers and team-lead

Technologies: Java, Selenium Webdriver, Rest Assured, Rest, etc...

OSs: Linux and Windows Server

Tools: Postman, Kubernetes, Docker, RDP, SSH, Oracle DB, PostgreSQL DB, MSSQL DB, Chrome DevTools.

- The second project was a product for marketing engaging customers with Web UI and also there was a plugin for Salesforce. Another product was CRM with Salesforce integration and plugin as well (including Salesforce mobile). I was the only QA Automation engineer in my sub-team responsible for automated and manual testing. We were working in very close collaboration with our stakeholders in California, US.
 - Team: 4 front-end devs, 4 back-end devs, team-lead, 2 QAs
 - Technologies: Java, Selenium Webdriver, Rest Assured, Appium, APEX, SOAP, Rest, etc... Tools: Postman, SSH, Jenkins, Chrome DevTools
- The third project was a product for managing IOT devices such as power meters, relays, AC/heating systems, etc with WebUI. I was the only QA engineer in my team responsible for automated and manual testing. We were working in very close collaboration with our stakeholders in Germany.

Team: 5 front-end devs, 6 back-end devs, team-lead, QA, 2 DevOps

Technologies: Java Script, Cypress, Gitlab CI, etc...

Tools: Postman, RDP, SSH, Docker, Chrome DevTools.

 The last project was an event managing platform with mobile apps (iOS and Android) for consumer and business customers. I was leading the QA subteam and was responsible for all testing and product quality from scratch. We successfully achieved the MVP and continued to uphold product quality, despite the rapid pace of development. Our team worked in very close collaboration with our stakeholders in Germany and another team of engineers in Greece.

Team: 2 front-end devs, 4 back-end devs, 3 Android devs, 3 iOS Devs, designer, business analyst, 4 QA

Technologies: Java Script, WebdriverIO+Appium, Rest, GraphQL, etc...

Tools: Postman, Appium Inspector, iOS simulator, Android emulator, Github Actions,

Jenkins

QA Engineer | Lohika | Odesa, Ukraine

August 2014 - August 2017

Lohika (later acquired by Capgemini Engineering) is a digital authority that advises and provides at the cutting-edge of technology. With US headquarters in San Mateo, CA and European headquarters in Lviv, Odesa, Kyiv (Ukraine) the company employed more than 1500 people in offices in 2021.

 The project was related to lifecycle management software. We were testing patch releases for desktop apps (client side) and server side, and were responsible mainly for regression testing along with installation/configuration testing.

Team: 5 QA, team lead.

Tools: HP UFT (QTP), SSH, RDP, Oracle DB, MSSQL DB.

OSs: Windows (desktop and server), Linux

EDUCATION

 Odesa National Polytechnic University | Masters in Information security and automated processing | September 2007- June 2012

SKILLS

- Java Script
- Java
- Cypress
- Appium
- WebdriverIO
- Selenium
- Rest Assured
- TestNG
- Mocha
- NodeJS
- Postman
- Docker
- PostgreSQL
- MSSQL
- Gitlab CI
- Github Actions
- Jenkins
- BrowserStack
- Jira
- Zephyr
- Test Rail
- Really good in investigating root cause of bugs
- Have good communication skills
- Team management